

JUSTIN DEWIEL

justindewiel@gmail.com | 419-496-6115 | Orlando, FL

Summary

Digital professional with more than 13 years of experience developing and executing award-winning strategy and creative looking for the right opportunity to partner with a determined team ready to push boundaries while driving business impact.

Skills

- Digital & Social Strategy
- Creative Strategy & Production
- Community Building
- Influencer Marketing

- Content Strategy & Planning
- Paid Media Strategy
- Consumer Experience (CX)
- Partnership Marketing

Experience

Global Director of Brand Marketing, Madden NFL

04/2019 - Current

Electronic Arts | Orlando, FL

- Lead the Madden NFL global marketing team responsible for the development, execution and measurement of the integrated omni-channel, consumer-facing Madden NFL marketing activations, with a focus on building player relationships and delivering on commercial goals worldwide.
- Drive coherent and consistent player journeys in line with Madden NFL story that are integrated across owned and partner channels, to drive player acquisition and compelling engagement that is globally cohesive and locally nuanced to deliver on commercial goals.
- Apply player, market and product insights, along with business objectives and strategies, to define marketing activation approach, tactics and KPIs.
- Allocate and manage deployment of annual Madden NFL marketing budget, optimizing investments throughout the year according to campaign and channel performance.
- Oversee cross-functional and partner collaboration to ensure consistent and timely execution across all channels, both owned and partner, to deliver on campaign goals and strategies.

Director of Digital Marketing/Head of the LEAD

02/2015 - 04/2019

Nestle USA | Solon, OH

- Built 30+ member digital center of excellence/content studio (The Lead) from the ground up and led the group on a day to day basis across multiple locations. To date, we have brought digital strategy, content strategy and planning, creative development, content production, community management, influencer marketing, and analytics in house for all digital and social work.
- Unlocked more than \$12MM in annual savings while also increasing pre-testing, brand lift and marketing mix quality scores through the work that has been executed by the internal team.
- Manage non-working budget to drive creative against a working digital media budget of \$250MM+ to drive effective ROI across all digital touch points.
- Partner closely with external agencies on TV creative strategy to maintain a consistent look and feel for each brand while also maximizing creative impact to ensure digital first executions.
- Manage partnership relationships with Facebook, Google, YouTube, Twitter, Instagram, and Pinterest to identify new opportunities and drive overall efficiency in digital buys while unlocking new creative ways to deliver brand messaging.

Senior Digital Communications Manager

10/2007 - 02/2015

Electronic Arts | Orlando, FL

- Led comprehensive cross-channel digital communications strategy that defined objectives and measured effectiveness across 30+ EA brands on social, web and mobile.
- Set content strategy and editorial calendar plans for 300+ EA social channels to drive interaction with 400MM+ fans on a daily basis.
- Collaborated with internal cross functional teams on social, web, partnership marketing, brand, CRM, and PR to maximize campaign results.
- Delivered social media insights and measurement including: regular dashboards, analysis on content effectiveness and consistent user experience.
- Created and oversaw EA Game Changers program responsible for 10K pieces of content and 100MM+ views annually.

Education and Training

Bachelor of Science: Sociology, Pre Law, & Marketing Ashland University | Ashland, OH, United States

2007